[
  {
    "question": "What is the length of the WEP initialization vector (IV)?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": ["24 bits", "32 bits", "48 bits", "64 bits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the integrity check value (ICV) in WEP protect against message modification attack?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The ICV in WEP protects against message modification due to the integrity key",
      "The ICV in WEP protects against message modification by the error-detection property",
      "The ICV in WEP does not protect against message modification by an attacker",
      "The ICV in WEP protects against message modification by the challenge value"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"Michael\" in RSN ?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "Michael is the 32 bits sequence counter scheme used in TKIP",
      "Michael is the 64 bits block encryption scheme used in TKIP",
      "Michael is the 20 bits replay protection scheme used in TKIP",
      "Michael is the 64 bits message authentication code used in TKIP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the consequences of the Beck & Tews chopchop-like attack on TKIP?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "An attacker can avoid the re-keying interval of the MIC failure report frame",
      "An attacker can decrypt traffic and send packets with custom content",
      "An attacker can cause packets to be silently dropped",
      "An attacker can send packets with custom content over QoS channels"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the 128-bit start value for RSN CCMP encryption?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "8-bit flag, 104-bit nonce, 16-bit counter; where the nonce created 8-bit priority, 48-bit source address, 48-bit packet number",
      "128-bit fresh nonce",
      "16-bit flag, 104-bit nonce, 8-bit counter; where the nonce created 8-bit priority, 48-bit Source address and 48-bit packet number",
      "16-bit packet number, 112-bit nonce"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a mutable field in RSN CCMP?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "A header field that is modified in transmission to ease decryption operation",
      "A header field that may be modified in transmission",
      "An integrity protected header field that may be modified prior to transmission",
      "An encrypted header field that may be updated prior to transmission"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP)?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for mutual authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for upper-layer authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for RSN authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for RADIUS server authentication methods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The TKIP Pairwise Transient Key is a collection of several keys.",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "Pairwise Master Encryption Key (256 bits), Pairwise Master Data Integrity Key (128 bits), EAPOL-Key Encryption Key (64 bits), EAPOL-Key Integrity Key (64 bits)",
      "Pairwise Master Encryption Key (256 bits), Pairwise Master Data Integrity Key (256 bits), EAPOL-Key Encryption Key (64 bits), EAPOL-Key Integrity Key (64 bits)",
      "Data Encryption Key (128bits), Data Integrity Key (128bits), EAPOL Pairwise Master Encryption Key (256 bits), EAPOL Pairwise Master Integrity Key (256 bits)",
      "Data Encryption Key (128 bits), Data Integrity Key (128 bits), EAPOL-Key Encryption Key (128 bits), EAPOL-Key Integrity Key (128 bits)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the inputs of the GSM authentication function A3?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "\\(K_i\\) and RAND and XRES",
      "RAND and XRES",
      "\\(K_i\\) and XRES",
      "\\(K_i\\) and RAND"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the subscriber identity protected from radio channel eavesdropping in GSM?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "By a temporary subscriber identity",
      "By the subscriber key encryption",
      "By the tamper-resistant SIM card",
      "The subscriber identity is not protected in GSM, only in UMTS and LTE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the sequence number (SQN) used in UMTS?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Preventing replay attacks",
      "Preventing man-in-the-middle attacks",
      "Preventing session hijacking",
      "Enabling re-synchronization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is mutual authentication provided when a GSM SIM is used to access a UTRAN",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Yes, between the MS and the RNC",
      "Yes, between the MS and the core network, but not the RNC",
      "No, the GSM SIM cannot authenticate the base station",
      "No, the GSM SIM cannot connect to a UTRAN"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the content and use of the UMTS AUTS parameter?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "\\(SQN \\oplus AK, MAC-S\\). Resynchronization when the \\(SQN\\) check fails on the network side",
      "\\(SQN \\oplus CK, MAC-S\\). Resynchronization when the \\(SQN\\) check fails on the network side",
      "\\(SQN \\oplus AK, MAC-S\\). Resynchronization when the \\(SQN\\) check fails on the MS side",
      "\\(SQN \\oplus CK, MAC-S\\). Resynchronization when the \\(SQN\\) check fails on the MS side"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the purposes of the UMTS MILENAGE functions?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Message encryption and authentication",
      "Message encryption and session key generation",
      "Message and user authentication/confirmation, and session key generation",
      "Message authentication and session key generation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the output of the UMTS f9 algorithm?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "It is a 32-bit MAC",
      "It is an indefinite length keystream",
      "It is a 64-bit block ciphertext",
      "It is a 32-bit authenticated ciphertext"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the consequences of the Zhang & Fang redirection attack against UMTS authentication",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Because serving networks are not authenticated in UMTS, an attacker can redirect the traffic via servers abroad, causing roaming fees",
      "Because serving networks are not authenticated in UMTS, an attacker can learn the session keys",
      "Because core networks are not authenticated in UMTS, an attacker can redirect the traffic to an authentication center abroad, causing roaming fees",
      "Because core networks are not authenticated in UMTS, an attacker can learn the session keys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is the UMTS/LTE network domain security specifications for the core network sufficient to protect the authentication and key agreement messages against parallel session attacks",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "No, the network domain security does not necessarily protect the session identifier, but this cannot be exploited by an attacker",
      "No, the network domain security does not necessarily protect the session identifier and may allow session-mixup attacks",
      "Yes, the network domain specification demands the use of IPsec or MAPsec, and therefore the core network communication is protected",
      "Yes, but the core network communication is always assumed to be secure, independent of the network domain security specifications"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is forward key separation achieved during handovers over X2 connections in EPS",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "The target eNB gets a fresh key from MME immediately after handover",
      "The target eNB gets a fresh key from MME right before handover",
      "The source eNB provides a key KeNB to the target eNB by applying a one-way function to the old key",
      "Forward key separation is not achieved, only backward key separation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which attacks are prevented if an RFID reader authenticates to a tag?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "For instance, tracking of the tag",
      "For instance, distance measuring and tag blocking",
      "For instance, tag inventory registration",
      "For instance, illicit reading, cloning, and reprogramming of the tag"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the anti-counterfeiting measure â€œtrack and trace' for low cost RFID tags work?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "By reading tags regularly with centralized storage for date and location, then a tag is \"genuine\" if it has a valid item history",
      "By using a challenge & response protocol, where the tag must answer a random challenge by the reader",
      "By using a privacy-preserving identification protocol",
      "By observing the unique radio communication fingerprint of a tag"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the general steps performed by intrusion detection systems for mobile ad-hoc net works?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Data Collection and Retaliation",
      "Data Collection, Detection, and Response",
      "Node Detection, Obstruction, and Response",
      "Node Detection, Rendering, and Alarm"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the vulnerability of captive pages",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "The weak encryption can easily be broken",
      "There is encryption but no integrity protection",
      "There is integrity protection but no encryption",
      "Sessions can be hijacked"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the problem with MAC Sequence Number Analysis in Intrusion Detection Systems?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": "2012 Fall",
    "options": [
      "The MAC Sequence Number Analysis does not work at all because the sequence numbers are not integrity protected",
      "The MAC Sequence Numbers only protect against message replay attacks, but not against session hijacking",
      "Each class in QoS (WMM) has its own sequence number. Also an attacker can still hijack a session when the victim goes offline",
      "Implementations very often use a constant value as MAC Sequence Number, and, therefore, this does not even protect against replay attacks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between a checksum code and a cryptographic message authentication code?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "There is no difference, they are only different terms for the same primitive",
      "A message authentication code can be used to construct a checksum code, but not the other way around",
      "A checksum can be (re-)computed by an attacker, the authentication code cannot",
      "A keyed checksum provides stronger message integrity protection than a message authentication code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is it not sufficient to construct a one-way function \\(y = f(x)\\) based on an NP-hard problem?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The one-way property requires that the problem is NP-complete and not just NP-hard",
      "NP-hardness guarantees only that there exists a y for which a x is hard to compute",
      "A one-way function must satisfy the property of collision-resistance too",
      "Computing a preimage must be hard in the worst case"
    ]
  }
]
